technology with purpose goal-setting I
made a thumbnail and everything more
perfect we have our own thumbnail and
stock that great but it's better than
just our two heads now it's real yes
exactly
Oh No what's happening that's how what's
happening I have it on another channel
no that's me that's my voice could you
hear that or just me
I feel like here's something in the
background on I could hear it full-on
because although this but I guess it was
a plane in the air so it's only coming
through here gotcha we're good do you
remember what you agreed to two weeks
ago because I listened to you I did I
didn't do it but I do never all right do
you want to say what it was no sir
so it was going to be I guess deciding
on like the infographic or the the image
that I wanted to get improved and I
wasn't going to send it over to Dennis
to improve gotcha and I didn't do that I
did it was crazy last two weeks I did
however last night sort of start a new
one with some new ideas and sort of
better summaries of things um and then I
plan to send that to him later today
so hopefully for next week cool you know
I'll have some stuff in progress or at
least I can say that I sent it off and
you know keep going
cool I did not write down what I had
just watched I did like a five minute
video yesterday just going over the
previous week but I believe it was like
create two videos and do the
conversations and yes I overdid the
conversations I need to stop the
addiction of game be conversations that
are teaching over my life because I
really enjoy them but like I had a
three-hour conversation on Tuesday which
was supposed to be half an hour it went
like so wrong it went right it was like
a weird I didn't have any way I thought
it wasn't gonna have anyone show up to
the idea cafe for getting be and then
this guy showed up who thought he was
watching instead of participating Oh
everybody was like oh but okay I'll
participate I guess and and then Eric
showed up and so the three of us had it
as soon as we ended this got like Remzi
who run who is starting common planet
the dead Jubilee ended up popping in
even though I was like wait this isn't
like getting be cafe you know just up in
whatever anyway so we ended up having a
two and a half hour conversation after
the half-an-hour idea cafe on currency
and his idea of like a new currency and
and all of these things which I wish had
been recording cuz it was really
interesting and I like brims these ideas
even if I'm also critical of them so
that was like a three-hour conversation
and then the next day and which is also
when I had agreed to do both previous
week and then this week was like a 10 to
3 conversations as well as the board
meeting in Bentley and I had yesterday I
came on live myself last Saturday for
five minutes looks like here's what I
did here's what I'm doing this coming
week I have finished all of the videos
for the video series on what to the
other tech is and what it what it can do
I have a couple more that I want to do
but I can kind of do those well I'm
really seeing the other ones because I
have the main all the ones that need to
be there including this morning I did
the introduction and how to get involved
if you like the book ends and so I've
both been attending Congress realizing
that okay I need to UM not have three
hour long conversations because I don't
have the spoons to do that but I really
enjoy it and it's really hard in the
moment when I am energized and having
fun too like okay two hours is the limit
or an hour and a half is the limit
because in the next day was the
practicing Omega rule conversation and
we did I was like at two hours I was
like nope this can't go further because
if yesterday which Eric's in the in that
one as well and yeah so I did make the
limit so this week I don't know if I'm
gonna attend the Monday conversations
anymore although I really enjoy them
they're not mine and they're not they're
the one I can kind of cancel off without
packaging too much and they're the
longest like you watch for an hour and
then you talk for an hour to two hours
so it's it's a lot I do something during
the hour like I'm usually cleaning my
house and I'm nothing else is there I
might continue doing that otherwise all
I have is
days without anything but because of how
they are encounter anyway so the other
thing is as I have made my personal life
the not smoking pot the yoga and the
meditation which is definitely
continuing but I had added on a fourth
which was doing daily scoping for half
an hour and I'm no longer doing that
like it's just I'm so busy with
everything else that that's the one
thing that can go off the plate that
isn't really doesn't have the effect
that I thought it would have I don't
have I have like maybe 10 more
subscribers than I did before
starting that and on YouTube that might
be good on periscope that's not like
people are like brand new and they have
50 people watching I'm like I have five
people I don't know how to interact with
people on here this is not my my thing
I'll just go on when I what I want to
and learning what I need to learn as I
as I learn it so I'm going to be
releasing the videos I'm just gonna
start Torro on December 1st because it's
the first but instead I'm going to start
it in December 4th because it's
grandma's birthday I don't know
feels like a good a good day to start if
it's not going first and I'm not gonna
be ready for tomorrow so that is what
I'm going to I did everything I was
supposed to do and more is really what
it came down to he said I'd do two more
videos and I finished them and now I
need to actually like who did the
thumbnails and put them in but I need to
like late to the next one and they're
all in a playlist and I need to actually
listen to them and write the description
in each of them and then I can start
really see them do I then do the
schedule right so if they were to prefer
private to public each day at 9:00 a.m.
right whatever cool and that is what I
will be doing this week but also what I
wanted to mention you would mention
before we went live an introvert unlike
marketing for introverts networking yeah
networking for introverts and that's
actually not networking but marketing
too and for introverts is what we are
somewhat struggling with with idea cafe
and so maybe I'll get your help in in
crowdsourcing that like by whoo crowd I
mean you use sources
tell me tell me how to do it a crowd of
one yeah so I think that is maybe I can
just say that because we said our goals
are and I will say what our new goals
are at the end right I mean I don't
really introvert is specific enough to
to market towards think I'm not sure
what marketing to introverts what will
look like instead of you know making
sure that whatever way they have to take
hold of you is you know like chat or
like you know super easy and not like
anyone know so so that's these so this
is that wasn't the thing that I need
help with it was just the intro to the
thing I need help with so idea Cafe
itself is perfectly designed for
introverts but they don't know it is the
issue and the way that it currently is
is on YouTube which is definitely not
designed for introverts right so I'm
part of these conversations the Omega
rural conversations on the Wednesday and
one of the ones we had identified talked
to you after I had the first one I don't
think so we missed
anyway it became me and this other girl
that woman have are introverts and two
of the other ones are extroverts and
then like Eric was in the middle of an
ambivert I guess honestly I'm kind of
Gordon and before but um Heather and I
are both like oh these video
conversations are great because we don't
have all of this information coming at
us or as the introverts for like we need
that extra information or say the
extroverts were like we need that extra
information like we can't read the room
we can't feel the feelings we can't wear
as Heather and I were like oh this is
amazing this is this is a good a good
process and now I kind of had mentioned
out to Heather the next time and she had
said she has participated in idea Cafe
and she was like well the five minutes
at the beginning doesn't necessarily
work you're on stage you know like that
feels good feels like you the spotlight
on you not fun French words but also
part of that is is making it obvious
that is voluntary when she did what it
was literally just the two of us so it's
somewhat not voluntary I'll share and
then we'll have a conversation I guess
but you know it was also near the
beginning but making it more
obvious what is expected as I think that
also is something that introverts like
is having things lined out to know to
not have all of that guessing work of
like wait what do they say what am I
saying
rehearsing in my head you know all of
all of that and so I think we like in
the current world you can't market
something I you can't market a solution
to something people don't understand
that they have a problem too right
introverts don't know they don't that
social media doesn't necessarily they
know social media doesn't work for them
they don't necessarily know that this
one knows and so because of the like
broken extroverted social media of like
Oh video is very public and very trolli
and very this is a different format
where it's like how so how do we get
introverts on board to say what's
working for them to say what's not
working for them and to design this
specifically for introverts because it
already is designed for them extroverts
already gonna lose something because
it's online but they're gonna get to
talk so yeh I think that's where as
introverts they gain something from this
that they don't even understand until
they participate in it and so I don't
know how to part of it is having idea
cafes that directly target feels like
the wrong word but target introverts
right of like here's what and Bentley
and I worked on that a little bit
yesterday of questions which I don't
have with me at the moment but questions
that are specifically designed French
first like what is the benefit of being
an introvert or how does it what kind of
conversation or space makes you feel
safe to talk and share your ideas even
if that's not an introvert you know like
as an introvert necessarily isn't egged
on at the end but I think that is the
type of question that like an introvert
hopefully you know if you can get
attention from both rooms it's you know
pretty telling just to figure out what
is the difference because if everyone
gives the same answer that that tells
you one thing if you have two groups
giving very different but like oh you
know this is like 40 60 if 50 as far as
the groups are split mm-hmm
very interesting yeah and so how was the
networking for introverts what did they
suggest in the networking for introverts
because that is a piece of advice
it was pretty loosely organized like we
were each given a card with like a
question to ask the group which I think
maybe only one person did the
conversation still happened fairly
organically because it's just you know I
think there's a five of us standing
around a like small table and I got
there was like it had already been going
for a few minutes and it's just a
conversation
but it was I guess part of it was
knowing like okay if somebody signs up
for a networking for introverts event
right they're gonna have probably
certain things in common and yeah it was
okay and I think that that was the one
where it was like just coincidentally
did the guy I had worked for a telecom
that had sold the boy to ice and yeah
it's always good like oh so you're
actually like is early panic all the
fight to talk about this yes yes
absolutely
just a conversation we were having
before we we would like um yeah so I
still I mean it's just a problem that
doesn't really have a solution just part
of being transparent is just be
transformed to vote those things like
right we want introverts tell us how to
get tell us how to market to you tell us
how good tell you what your pain is so
badly was talking about I don't quite
understand it but I think it's powerful
even if I don't understand it is with
marketing that you either give a vitamin
or a painkiller but it's like kind of
the solution or the cure to their pain
right until aim of it in that manner and
sitting with those questions there was
also of course because we have that
conversation I'm getting targeted ads on
Facebook for like how to kind of make an
elevator pitch in one of those like
rhoda bucks and I asked if they have a
money-back guarantee and they were like
yeah of course but you'll love it not
necessarily it's very very game a
sometimes things that are game a don't
Solutions checking and sometimes it's
super like oh I've already heard all
this a thousand times and the person
just saw because if somebody's good at
selling it all that means that they're
good sigh I just mean that they're good
at teaching people how to sell yeah no
exactly another part of it is they are
their advertisement made it clear that
wasn't the case but that doesn't mean
it's not the case yeah that's what the
money-back guarantees were like yeah
it's great but it just wasn't great in
the way that your ad said it was yeah
well it wasn't good for my orbitals
which is why I need it and so and it's
not a huge investment I'm not willing
and I also have this woman tell me about
this incubator guy it was like
incubators are not my thing I'm not
spending hundreds of thousand or a
thousand dollars to create technology
that Google's gonna buy that's not
overdoing I understand that those people
who would be in innovators yes I want
them on board including if they can see
the vision of what it is to be a
technology cooperative but not to follow
game a and so we can you know make it
lucrative for investors right yeah kind
of like a no-go area for you but that's
like no that's and the struck like I
wouldn't trust that an incubator could
help you because all the advice that
they're gonna be giving you is on
building a for-profit thing to
eventually sell well but there are
pieces that like marketing marketing
into a degree especially at this stage
it's like I hate marketing and we need
to learn how to market that's just I
mean I think the main thing like the
kind of marketing principle that you'd
want is as a full name but it's from a
book called bridging the gap thinking
it's about marketing new technologies to
the public and it's about sort of who do
you start with how do you move to the
next group and the next group of the
know until you have pretty much everyone
and yeah I've known many companies and
many people that have sort of had that
as their Bible for rolling out new new
like technology and new innovations that
like you know now if you're buying a
cell phone that's you know everyone has
one but if you're like selling some
crazy new tech web software or hardware
order yeah like I think a third option
but any of those it's like you know you
do start with
a small slice that are sort of the early
adopters that are willing to you don't
use something that isn't fully ready and
like it's hyper focused on them and then
you sort of how do you move to the next
group and the next group in it is like
yeah you can't really make one product
out of the gates is going to work for
everyone so it's about where do you
start and then how do you move the
product and your marketing to go to the
next group in the next trip and Dean
expert and nicely I know that sounds
like a good a good option and if it's
popular enough I can probably get from
the library that I don't go to every six
months dude it's also pretty good chance
that like there will be some good
YouTube videos like you know if it may
not be by the author but that concept
has been out there for a while now so
it's probably some good did you think
yeah pretty sure that's the name did
really good got some it
oh no crossing the chasm like so is
similar wait is there it's something gap
like yeah crossing degrees because it's
a gene crossing because I kind of what
could quickly do it
yeah Jeff anymore okay that's the one
Bentley had sent are tweeted am a video
called hacking consciousness with Josh
so Joshua fields rabbit was done and
it's basically like how do we force
people to get in lightnings he comes off
much better than that but it's like what
it's gonna use like that questions fine
with me I'm not because I think that
forcing people to become enlightened
it's not how you get people I think it's
going to you know be fruitful but I
think it's an interesting question
nonetheless
yeah that's not he comes across my
traders not but there's pieces of it run
like Silicon Valley deciding how to
release things to enlighten us all is
not what I want to do like I want to
like actually ask people do you want
this this is a product for you right
like to offer to people do
- you know see your shadow side and
improve it do you want to like what is
it you actually want they're talking
about I've been watching a lot of Jordan
Peterson not so much the last week but
like the week previous to that and I
have this Twitter follower who like both
followed and then unfollowed me based on
my Jordan Peterson it's like you're
critical of him I'm like yeah I am he's
critical of him and I'm not gonna of
course I'm gonna pick the piece that I'm
critical of to talk about right like I
was talking about the Joe Rogan podcast
with Bret and I'm like I'm not talking
about Bret because I agreed with
everything he said right like you're
talking about where they disagree on not
see and Brent goes up talking about he
has a Doran's like hold on I just want
to say I agree with everything you just
said because I don't want somebody
taking their he like he disagrees oh
yeah I don't remember that part of it
but yeah that's right but in a spiritual
group I'm part of one of them it's like
something's shamanism like mental
illness for shamanism or chauvinism
prevents illness or something ridiculous
and wonderful like that and someone put
a Jordan Peterson quote which is
basically like you have to go through
hell to get enlightened that's why there
aren't that many enlighten people going
around but I was a picture of him with
Jordan Peterson people are like no it
was like do you agree with the quote who
cares we said it right to a degree and
so people are like well he's a neo-nazi
he doesn't believe in white privilege
I'm like those are two different things
I think you're ignorant if you can't see
white privilege but he's a white
able-bodied male who works like of
course he doesn't see white privilege
was age like and he's what a
psychologist that is an astronomer he's
worked with a lot of white people so he
works with sort of people who are down
and out because if somebody who's not
going to believe in it you can kind of
see how he might not he himself might
you know believe in his own areas of it
but it's like looking but is it because
I'm white yeah like he doesn't believe
in the patriarchy he does I'm like you
need to listen to people of color you
need to listen to women it doesn't mean
that it's right
I hear the conversation and I totally
okay I don't like the word choice and
the way that they talk about it I agree
with a lot of the end points but like
and I've heard of stuff on the
patriarchy it dives
really deep and like you talks about
sort of the pros and cons beats each
side yeah I agree that the world isn't
like all four men none for women at the
same time the patriarchy that like white
men are in charge is hurting everybody
even if it's also like of course it's
also hurting white men the point isn't
every white man's okay and everyone
who's not isn't and some people treat it
that way
absolutely and basically that's what
these people are doing they're like he
did not see I'm gonna punch him in the
face I'm like not believing in the white
supremacy or sorry I've never heard him
say that racism doesn't exist no yes a
straight like all that there's you know
a lot of it he goes off like Jordan
Peterson replies to things and somebody
who asked him like hey there's not see
that you're again what do you have to
say sort of pauses and thinks about like
that
Henny replied if he's like I don't like
Nazis they're bad like what do you want
me to say no it just they're like he's a
Nazi I'm like he needs to be punched in
the face I'm like and they said he's a
vile blah blah blah I'm like so I think
the definition of Nazism if we're gonna
like start labeling people is to
categorize somebody as subhuman and
therefore worthy of violence you're the
one who just did that right like you're
literally the notes yeah I totally a
great people were like you know punching
noises okay I do agree with that the
problem is that we've been using that
word so much it's lost basically all
meaning and we just say everyone that
you know that disagrees with us is a
Nazi now if we say that you can punch
that person then we just said if you
disagree with somebody you you can punch
them is essentially what is gonna boil
down both sides of that which isn't
great which I think is in the Joe Rogan
where they're talking about how like if
you can't admit that maybe you could
have been a Nazi right that like you if
that is literally the Deaf because I was
looking I'm like can I could I do not
see yeah like honestly the fact you
asked that probably means you're less
likely to be but also unlike no actually
I wouldn't and it's not because I'm
better than it's because I don't think
that less than means I got to instill
violence on you
even if you make someone subhumans first
of all you basically can't make someone
some humans meet and even if you did I
don't think they deserve violets right
like I don't believe in the death
penalty for anyone you know what I mean
so I'm like actually no I'm not but it's
not because it's like the people who are
like no they're horrible kill all the
Nazis I'm like you're a Nazi like that
is literally okay just take up the first
word and you're like okay what's the
first word I have to figure out if I'm a
offended or not yeah exactly
kill all the blames hold up for me yeah
exactly right but it's so common like
that's even and this is not about Nazism
and this is possibly my own why it's
always my own that's what I'm here
to deal with it so we're all here to
deal with and but I've tried to start
there's this I don't know if you know
teal Swan said the name she's like very
spiritual she like does I don't even
know she like is in touch with something
from the other side and I like her
videos most of them there's very few
stuff she says the stuff she says that's
too far out for me but they don't think
she says that I feel is wrong
she's been criticized rather recently
for her stance on suicide and I did a
video this week on that and I stand by
what I said that liked her anyway that's
not the point I'm talking about so I
posted in one of the new teal salon
groups has heard big 20,000 people one
got dismantled because of her stance on
suicide which was basically like you
have your own right to do that but don't
do that let's help people the regular
mental health system doesn't help it
isolates them which is exactly what they
don't need to be told that you know what
I mean like I'm hurting and I'm isolated
okay so we're just gonna pull you up
with you in a padded room right which is
like even if you don't kill yourself
that week it doesn't help you in the
future
where is her stance is like is
controversial but like actually helps
most people but some people still kill
themselves less people than anyway so
that's kind of for me the metric is the
data are you less likely or more likely
father's name strings improved in this
way yeah exactly because like
alternative anything like
we don't look at the regular course of
healthcare the regular course of benzoyl
health care as if you killed yourself
it's their failure but if your
alternative we look at it as your
failure right and so that's a big huge
issue and so I posted in this in the
group that she has this other so I
watched a video so many things on her
with this woman with chronic pain and
her stands on basically anything is if
you're trying to change it you're not
loving it and therefore you're doing
yourself a disservice right you have to
first love it and like accept your child
self accept all of those things in order
to ever hope to heal it but if you're
doing it to heal you're not accepting it
right so it's like that weird like you
kind of need to accept it as it is and
that's exactly what I'm in the irony is
then people are like but you're not
healed so you're not doing it right I'm
like no I'm in the loving it stage like
it's like that's fine it's not you can't
push through it you can't get faster
beyond she has this other video on
healing your mind it is basically
meditate love yourself where you're at
right and then once you're ready once
you're really good at that then you
could offer yourself the healing then
you can offer yourself the counter to
what your body needs or your mind needs
or whatever it is but until you can get
to truly accepting it and loving that
you can't get there so I posted that I
wanted to find other people who have
chronic illness who want to go through
that journey together who want to like
show up on video to showcase that with
other people and just like have a
conversation every two weeks so this
woman contact me was like yes that's
what I want to do and then we kind of
talked on the phone and it was clear she
kind of wanted to she's like well I have
this this service or this thing that I
do and I was very you are and it was
like that's not what I'm looking for I'm
looking for peer to peer like I'm
looking for this group that we're all in
together and it doesn't matter where you
are in your journey because this isn't a
anyone who's been on any journey it's up
and down like it's not like oh you
didn't progress you're failing it's like
you progressed you go back a little and
forward and back and but you know it's
like you hopefully get a little more and
more forward hopefully but even if
you're doing it to do that you're
already breaking it and that's like the
the irony of it all of the healing
process in general is like if you're
trying to heal you're breaking it even
there to heal it's like yeah anyway this
woman's like well yeah I've already
healed right at six months on and it's
like alright well then you're probably
not the person yeah but she so I but she
wanted to do it and I was like cool
awesome yeah let's do it let's pick a
time and I sent her the idea cafe links
cuz I was like that's her we're gonna do
it and I said I was like all of the ones
in the last few weeks are game B they're
very logical very left brain very like
ours will be the opposite of that right
and she was like can I give you some
honest feedback was like yeah I'm always
hoping on honest feedback and she was
basically like you come off very
masculine and logical I was like yeah I
was like yeah it's maybe a train where
I'm doing interpretive dance on game
beans I'm like oh you're very and she
was like what is gay B I'm like that's
not what we're doing either like you
know what I mean like this is a
different piece of meat eel so
unspiritual like figure out Omega rule
is as close as I'm getting to that
within the game be space and it's
amazing and people that are looking to
evolve and they're looking it's not less
than in any way in fact anyway but she
was basically like you're too logical
that was me six months ago so I don't
want to have this conversation I was
like wait you're clearly like she's like
well that was my defense mechanism I'm
like I'm not even saying it so clearly
your defense mechanism just based on the
story and that's like I'm like because
if you loved it and you accepted in
yourself you wouldn't be triggered by
mine and you also like I'm like she was
just like giving me more stuff to learn
she's like do you unis didn't even think
about that and like responded I'm like
yeah because it was nothing new like
it's not like it would even trigger me I
was like masculine and logical that's me
epic she's like you didn't even put a
new feeling language in it I was like no
I didn't but then I saw that I was like
why do I keep attracting these people to
my life they want to be my mentor and
teacher but that's not what I want
I have mentors and teachers I like tille
Swan I like Kyle cease I like the people
in game B that are like Jordan Peterson
who showed us already dr. Peters and
Jordan Hall um who don't pretend to be
the experts right they're like like they
have a different energy if you think
you're better then I'm not here to learn
from you and maybe that's my but
like that's just not the Enter
that calls to me if we're peer-to-peer
I'm gonna learn from you
anything you say I'm gonna learn what
I'm gonna trigger something in me but if
you need to be in a hierarchy over me
it's already not working I have the same
problem or anything like that and I'm
like and so but part of me was like well
what is like am I not learning what I'm
here to learn because I keep getting
these people and if I wasn't gonna kind
of tell her the like tell her what she
was doing wrong it was like that would
be the same thing I'm like I can learn
what I'm here to learn I'm okay with
where I am in my journey the fact you're
six months on in the healing journey
first of all I've been doing this for
three years you're not six months on on
me you don't know you've had one
conversation yes you're maybe more
feeling and logical than I am but even
then like I'm solved that's not like
that's not how this pretty good you got
by this I'm gonna say probably not
anyway so so she told me she didn't tell
me she was like she suggested that teal
Swan app they just got created and I'd
already seen it advertised so I was like
actually I met to look at to see for how
expensive it was and it was like six
bucks so I was like yes I will pay 6
bucks missed one and it's basically
tarot cards and that like you've kind of
pick one and it will kind of tell you
it's a blind spot tarot card so it's
like blind spots that you have and the
first one I picked so I got downloaded
this and like this whole thing of like
what your ID but the whole first part
was like you are looking for too much
external validation I'm like that's
really not my problem but then the last
one was like no you're you're if you
sometimes have to listen to experts but
if you pulled this card this is not it
and I was like thank you that is that is
exactly I was like am I not finding the
expert in other people and then I pulled
a conflict one between me and syriza and
it was perfect and then I pulled this
like past present future one that was
like me and the past one I don't
remember what they were like I have them
saved on my iPad like I was like this is
really really weird and it's kind of
like that dad Millman book that we read
together I was like I don't even believe
in this but somehow the numerology is
perfect except
but it was like oh it is perfect it's
that kind of a thing where when it
resonates and I don't I I mean I think
tarot cards work that way that it is
random and then it's what you speaks to
you through your subconscious that is
the true part but these things were so
spot-on the issue is because it was the
first card I pulled I thought its name
was sigil like I thought that was the
name of the card like you know twelve
aces or whenever my actual tarot cards
are called but it isn't they're all
called sigil oh so it's like this
digital means and I was like oh so I've
known T what the card actually was that
I pulled but I was like this is because
it was so wrong it was right like I was
like it was giving me the office advice
of what I was asking like it was telling
me that yes you're right
see internally even though the card
itself is for people exceeding
externally I was internally and it was
giving me permission that was like those
things keep and and so that was one of
the the past present future ones was
like the future one was like look for
the signs and I was like that's exactly
what I'm doing is looking for the signs
in life and following them like the
necklace falling off of those things
like the more you're the more you follow
the next sign the faster they come and
I'm like yep that's what I'm
experiencing and it is like yeah you're
doing the right thing it was like and I
don't remember the present one was in
the past one was very heat like it was
like you've been following other
people's advice up till now it was
basically what it was and now you like
now and I was like if that was the past
like that was why I'm broken it's
falling everyone else's advice and yet
it wasn't the same card as the other one
and I don't remember what the present
one was was like yeah it's like these
are weird so weird but I'm gonna use it
everyday cuz even if it's just calling
for my subconscious right to tell me
like oh this is the thing yes even if
it's just a stepping stone to get you
some sort of different thought yeah yeah
absolutely because right now by my
process is waiting to be triggered by
the outside and then dealing with it
right like Jordan Peterson triggers be
cool what am I here to learn this woman
triggers me what am I here to learn
right like it's like she triggers me
because I'm triggering her and I'm like
well there's something there and that's
why I was like wait am I supposed to be
learning the teacher thing or am I
supposed to be yes I'm not I'm not
looking for a teacher and that is true
and it's like well listen
listed internally which one feels right
it's pretty perfect and then of this
woman at cohousing it's doing this
shaman exercise and I had dinner with
her last week or the week before and she
was talking about this soul retrieval
process and how she is doing it it's
kind of like that like it's it's but
with a shaman and she's learning how to
do the processes she did it for one of
the other peers in her group and got
something that didn't mean anything to
heard when she gave it to him and
something deep right and say much like
the person who didn't in hers I think is
who did it hers and she got something
that didn't really make sense to either
of them until she had a few days and was
like oh it was this she offered to do a
soul retrieval for me but she's in
Hawaii right now and I was like yeah
free I love her like I was like all all
the things take off like I'm willing to
try basically anything then the thing
that really because I was already a yes
but during the two on video with the
woman with chronic health yeah pain
chronic pain is what she says she had
said like you have a victim mentality
and you need to do like do part of it is
lit allowing other people to like help
you and finding someone to do with soul
retrieval it was like weird I've never
heard the word before I know it was like
video and those things happen constantly
where it's like I've gotten told three
times and I have to get the book is how
to have difficult conversations of
friends and like okay the third time I'm
told about a book I you have to check
out this person I'm like I don't got
time to put in an external knowledge I
just don't unless it comes to me it's
different if someone's like there's this
book I read then I'll be like wait tell
me about it if someone's like you need
to read this book I'm like mm-hmm
that's area where we're very similar and
that's that everyone you mean I peers
are all like we weren't really likely
told like if you have something
interesting to say say it and all just
if it's for me if you say like you have
to do this and instantly like tell me
what it is but I'm gonna take this with
a massive grain of salt
ya know which is actually an autistic
Mosley defiance disorder oppositional
it's like oh it's like if some authority
tells you you don't want to do it it's
like you're coming off as an authority
on my life no which is so the conflict
the conflict
into that on here
well have fun you do although I have
gone into it on Parris Goebel why not
but not with her name this is my
like I can only deal with my piece of it
even though a big piece of it is needed
her to change it's like okay that can't
be the piece it can't be because you
can't have anyone ever change it has to
be your own learning to get to the place
of no area you're like I know this is
where you know the this is the piece
that goes here but I don't like it I
need a different piece that's not how
puzzles work that you want figure it out
around that yes yes and it's amazing
because it does like it's like I do feel
the universe is like a loving bitchy
parent like I'm it's kind of why I'm
weird but like a like it's it's kind of
loving but not client's at all it's like
you didn't learn your lesson you need to
keep eating your vegetables I don't want
to do and we're just gonna give you the
same one I get them and again and again
until you figure it out and it is it's
like there is still then this is where
like we can't compare each other's
journeys because and I get I do get
jealous of people who have health
journeys who are like fixed it like I
because it's like it looks like I'm not
trying and I'm trying very hard and at
the same time part of that trying hard
got me to the place of loving and
accepting it so I'm not trying and it's
like like this my nervous system shuts
down under stress makes me sound like
I'm the weakest person on the planet and
quite frankly I had to kind of go
through a stage of being a very weak
person and now I'm like I'm
strong like I'm like because I had
stress was so poisonous and still is
I've had to de-stress things that are so
stressful for other people then it's
like oh yeah good because I can't like
so my social anxiety it basically how to
get over my social anxiety because it
was stressful and so it's like if I need
to leave my house I need to not care
what people think about me I have to
find my like true essence of who I am
and show up in the world in that way
because I can't deal with the stress of
caring what people think about me
because it shuts me it just shuts the
nervous system yeah
that thing was a challenging then you
had to adapt to it and now that what
that a patient is a strength yes exactly
and that is like it's because there's
times where I'm like can I just freaking
sit and write something it's like no
it's too stressful I have to wait till I
get the like spark and then just allow
it to happen it's like I don't know if
you have this process but I know how to
type like I can type and I if I'm not
thinking about it I can type pretty fast
and accurately but when I start thinking
about it I suck at it and it's like that
it's like well if I try to plan it out
too much I can't do it but if it's if
it's just like allowing the process and
that's like just surrendering to the
universe and sprinting to my path is my
path and yet society's not big on that
so it's like no me not stops the path
but it's like the more I'm able to just
be like 'even if at all if all of you I
love you all I'm saving the world for
you but I can't give up what you
think is basically my life and so it's
like the more I'm truly able to do that
and that was part of the Jordan Peterson
um Weinstein thing is I did a video that
was basically like wow both of these men
are famous because of controversy they
have important stuff to say but the
reason they have a platform is because
of the left basically vilifying them
which was a hilarious
Brett did was in this evergreen scandal
which is a college said I guess they had
this day where black people didn't have
to show up because of their history with
like not being able to be on campus and
they decided to flip it one year and ask
white people not not ask sorry no
demands white people not show up no
professors and no students he was like
that's which it is ridiculous
first off the whole thing is ridiculous
why would you celebrate getting getting
higher education by not coming to higher
education and then like wait if the
professors aren't there what are you
learning how yeah it's like that's great
I support you but if we're all working
towards bettering things like we're
gonna pause to better things to talk
about when things weren't better like
and we're not even talking about it it's
just like your day off exactly yeah it's
just again a pause like hey and yeah so
will you're guaranteeing that nothing is
going to be covered because also if you
did cover something important well the
other people are paying for that
it's like it's it's also a like it's not
voluntary right if they were like it's
not like it's like we should courage
people bla bla cool not showing up right
let's have the white people not show up
for the day and let's show them our
support when it's like you're not
allowed it's a completely different
feeling it's like then you show up and
you're like hi it's very similar to join
the Petersons thing right where he
became because of the whole you know the
like enforced I'm not gonna call people
by like that's not his thing people say
and he's like I swear he said you didn't
want it enshrined in law which I race
and he thing is you can have laws saying
what you can't say but this is the first
time that he said laws of things that
you have to say yeah yeah that's
dangerous ground and like I saw an
interview where it was like he was on
some news channel was a bunch of people
and there was a trans person who sort of
said like I don't you know dr. Peterson
probably wouldn't call me bye-bye
proponent bla bla bla and the whole look
will wait let's get an answer on that
and they said if she was in your class
would you used the pronoun that you know
she wants she he's like yes I would
it was just that was it like and he he
dives deeper into it in a different like
he did some talk at I think it was at
Cornwall or Oxford or some like that
where where somebody asked him about
Eddie said like given a background in
psychology there's you know there are
people who genuinely need to be called
that I called Matt but they're people
who are just doing it I mean yeah this
better phrasing to attend this but
basically because it's a power trip and
I won't be do that I won't call it to
you because it's our trip yeah right
trip and it's an auto power trip because
that's a power trip well but but so he
said he's like I'm willing to take two
to take that risk because of my sort of
background and training and somebody
will ask how can I do that and he's like
if you have to ask you probably can't
use like button also I should say I've
never done it he's like I mean I I
resisted to having the rules in place
he's like but I have never actually had
a situation where someone has asked me
to or I felt that they were having a
power trip so he's like every every time
that somebody has asked me to
I have which is which is really weird
given the stuff given the way he talks
yeah his followers aren't gonna be able
to distinguish and they'll be like
you're having a power trip but it's like
it's no you don't even straight which
that's the thing that's really weird
because his whole thing is like taking
taking responsibility and approving
yourself like aren't those like isn't
that the message you want Nazis to have
like hey work on yourself
yes clean your own room absolutely and
it's like well yeah that's strange it's
like so wait so people who need help or
seeking out your help well what do you
have to say about that good no
which is I think he's doing an amazing
job for the people who's doing it I'm
like he's doing he needs to be doing the
work he's doing the issues like he's a
lot of videos where he goes off on
social isn't that fair enough I agree
with all those points but like no story
well the socialism fascism are bad and
then go off on socialism but I've never
once heard of talk about why fascism is
bad for more like three seconds and like
you yeah maybe burn context I'd be
interested to hear his I think it's also
though he he hasn't really studied it
well oh and honestly his ideas on
socialism is like human nature works
that were different so we have to we
have to reward us in different ways and
like those two things aren't equated yes
we're different there's not going to be
a quality of outcomes that doesn't mean
you get to be rich and step on everyone
because you have a higher life because
you happen to be lucky and you have all
these intelligence and connections and
people who don't get to start like those
two things don't need to be in alignment
just because they are not like talk
about like that whole thing of you know
the people who are better get to succeed
talks about that baby the hierarchies
where he's like that it's an important
part they don't deep the right recruit
tends to sort of lean hard on that and
that taken to its extreme is fascism so
that's bad is then the left tends to
forget how you phrase it but he sort of
talks about like the people picking
apart that from the outside and he's
like an that take them to the to it to
initiate it socialism he's like but
those two I mean it as a balance to each
other which I agree like I think I'm
that's the issue and you vilified
the other side to make it subhuman
you're a Nazi does it matter and like
which side when it is it's like removing
the language so you can say wait what
are you seeing we do to these people
that sounds like not okay that sounds
like so so you you went around deputies
in the cabs okay I'm gonna stop you
there what does that sound like to you
which is because it becomes like if you
can remove the I got racism okay let's
remove the racism then this group of
people is doing X and they get Y and
this group is doing Y and X what what
does that look like to you right and
it's like oftentimes like we're moving
the racism shows the racism like it's
like like that Israel is hurting palace
in palace and they're like well we went
through the Holocaust so you decided to
do it again like that's what you're
doing then you have checkpoints are
unsafe and there are these people and
they're animals like never again so you
say never again
you man against you is basically what
we're here what would happen if as a
society as human beings we truly said
never again we would not be allowing
this to happen right and that is the
issue and yet there is a lot of like
right but there's history and like how
do we know what's happening in the
history and how do we allow with the
power to be shared and especially
because like we're watching it from the
other side of the world we're watching
that through the lens of the information
that's available which I think you all
know outside of it we don't trust that
information source really so we're like
oh I hope it's right this time no
exactly and it's like how much can you
trust and there's violence on both sides
but one side has rocks and the other
ones has rockets and like the you know
it's it's and the people who are in
charge of the rocks also are doing a
shitty shitty job of protecting their
people in fact they're putting them in
harm's way and which gave it like it's
just bad all around but like because
it's powers that be against powers that
be it's like everyone loses all across
the board just one side more than the
other and the more we can say okay what
is happening how do we trust it and then
how do we empower people who aren't in
power without making them in power right
like how do we empower people to witness
each other
what is actually happening removing race
while moving religion removing like who
got hurt who caused the herd how often
does this happen and who is doing what
and there are pieces about we can no one
like pretty black and white and there's
pieces that are not and very gray you
know that like a Roth a bomb went off
it's probably pretty 99 percent we know
it happens we don't necessarily know who
did it manufactured it
oh the us let's just you know I don't
know about the truth like what with the
bomb right whether or not yes I know you
take it up pictures and videos uh yeah
from a joint yeah something exploded but
it's very easy to take a video from ten
years ago of a bomb exploding and say
you know that happened in in Israel and
say no actually that happened in Syria
right yeah it's and that yeah that's
where I get super part like you know if
you watch it available on Israel and
Palestine it's a strong enough topic
that you're likely to come up with one
way or the other but so much of it is
based on what information you see yeah
really does it just gonna be like yeah
yeah we bomb them what are you going to
do about it
they have a pretty good reasoning behind
it let's you're like okay but are those
reasons true and is the other
information that I'm seeing true and
like yeah that's where it's you just
sort of have to like based information I
see from the news and from the new
sources I currently trust here's what I
think is happening but personally I'm
like I am always open to having my
opinions beliefs changed cuz I'm not
sure you know 99% of what I see like the
data shown to me from outside sources no
it's just sure like once you lose trust
in the system you've lost trust in the
system you're like I don't trust any of
it I'm gonna need a prove it to me yeah
that you know you need all sides proven
to you it's like no no how do we know a
bomb went off and that's an important
question to ask not necessarily when the
bomb goes off but long before to be look
how no when this happens well we have
cell phones there GPS there have time on
them they have like to know when was
this shot it was this recorded not
aborted recorded but but you you can say
that too yeah arguing and Martin me not
that many people are going to look at it
but like the whole thing in South Africa
is interesting we're like there I'm
seeing people post news about it and I'm
like I'm not see you in the mainstream
news so is it happening or not there's a
lot of there's a lot of this there's
like a lot of news articles and stuff
like that you're like if you're live
streaming if you have the internet if
you're live streaming and there's four
people doing it it's happening that's
where no indication and then there's a
thousand people who watch that who also
then back it up that like I watched it
like it was on a movie set or and even
then like if you're shooting it from
like multiple angles you're like that
couldn't be a movie I can see all the
different angles there's no camera crew
like yeah yeah and be lighting sucks and
it's like yeah yeah and that's the same
like that's a part of what the long-term
plans are for my thing is like okay take
a video of somebody you know of a
politician speaking at a rally great now
a hundred of you do it from different
angles different this from different
that you can't say it's fake anymore and
so it's like wait it's weird that all
the right-wing people have this part of
the speech and on the left wing people
have this but that's part of it if we
add that together we get the whole end a
lot of it we have the technology to say
okay here's the full hour of the clip
okay here's the part that people like to
pull out so anytime we see that clip
make sure to mention if you want to see
the full context here watch you know a
minute back here oh yeah they're ending
it up like and that's one of the things
that I'm actually sequestering computers
that doesn't get in trouble for more
it's just the way that he tells stories
it's like I listened to his audiobook
and the times were like what did he just
say
and I'm like oh it's cuz I can't you you
would tell it's like he say a quote that
somebody else would say but he's saying
it like he's saying it and like there
was some part where he was like don't
help people they'll help help themselves
blah blah I'm like whoa that's extreme
and there's the quote I'm like oh he's
saying that like as some as a point
somebody might try to make and then he
sort of counters it but the way he's
saying it sounds like he's just saying
it lucky please yeah that is because
that can be cut
yeah exactly and I'm surprised that this
thing I thirst exactly
ya know and it becomes that's why uh
Michael Moore if you interview him on
mainstream media he's like you're not
allowed to cut it it has to be the whole
thing and then he talks a long time that
my load
yeah hapless whenever he does end
because somebody else they're also
recording like you know just on a cell
phone or something so if they slice it
so like no here's the actual full clip
yeah sometimes you talk a long time and
you do need to cut it for ya which I
think cutting it's fine as long as it's
always done in context of like you know
here's the full clip and then also
there's times where it's like you'll see
like a really sketchy jump cut where
it's like the middle of a sentence
you're like okay what was the start of
that sentence like some people might say
blow up a blood and then they just cut
out that first part you're like oh so
you're just saying that like he's not
saying this it's obviously clear you did
this maliciously to try to smooth this
ya know by the way you need to watch
years and years which is a dystopian TV
show out of Britain and it's a the
scariest dystopian show because it takes
place now like it starts now and goes
ten years in the future and none of its
heart fetch not a single part of it it's
like that wouldn't happen like it's like
more refugees and more environmental but
like we're still alive we already it
doesn't become it never becomes Walking
Dead right there's no point where it's a
site for elliptic but like its dystopian
yeah exactly and so it's it's powerful
and yeah message buzz like it's the
scariest dystopian I've ever watched
because of that that being said ends on
like to cheer even actually right but
it's like even like technology like in
the Barrett I think it's the very first
one one of the the people who kind of
grows up
anyway she you know like how you have
picture filters like you can do a video
and you have your face covered it's
basically that in real-time but she's
like a little dear like I love you mommy
it's like does I can turn off the filter
it's like I feel like they wear
something that like projects uh yeah
it's like your face and like things like
kind of like they're taking porn
information in school like it's like you
know the like twelve year olds like oh
yeah you're an archetype of this
who's gay like it's like you're
projecting your misogynistic this and
that but it's like anyway and that's
just a tiny piece of it but it's like
the technology the right okay refugees
the the politics the something happens
at the end of the first one where you're
like wow and it's fairly like a blip in
kind of the whole series
you're like okay like a no lemons like
no I I have my slightly no I don't know
where to get it
oh where I get it but if you come and
bring your tablet I can sign you into
mine you can watch it bring your okay so
it's uh yeah I see I suggested highly
appropriate or well but it sounds
interesting I think was like gonna tell
you about what we're doing tomorrow but
let's go on live and then I will uh all
right be good by you to see anyone oh
wait did we say overdo a to the next
week let's quickly do that yeah we did
oh I guess I kind of did I'm doing the
thing that I said I was going to do but
didn't do I'm gonna you know finish off
the current order gets the newer version
of the infographic and intended to
dentists to make it look nicer to see if
it's something that's they're headed in
the right direction or can just be
shared as is perfect I am attending my
conversations - the one not doing scopes
anymore so doing the yoga meditation no
pot and as well as finishing up the
video series that is done that needs to
actually be like finished up so
physically be released in in the day
increments and that is what I am doing
alright YouTube see you next week